<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News Hiring Trends</title>
    <description>Stay up to date with the most popular programming languanges, databases, web application and software development technologies on Hacker News whoishiring posts</description>
    <link>https://www.hntrends.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.hntrends.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 04:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 04:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>&quot;Ask HN: Who is Hiring?&quot; postings fall to nine-year low</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;After a few months away, it's time to check back in on the &quot;Ask HN: Who is Hiring?&quot; trends. In May's thread, there are signs of growth again, a 35% improvement over April in fact. May saw the first 400+ posting month since May 2023. Not all that surpisingly, the rise of AI appears to be driving the growh. AI is mentioned in nearly 25% of job postings now and is the top technology term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2024/may.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full December rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.hntrends.com/images/202405-ask-hn-who-is-hiring-tot.png" length="90079" type="image/png" />
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 04:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2024/may.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2024/ay.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is Hiring? Job Postings fall to nine-year low</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;When I started this project ten years ago, I was mainly interested in studying and sharing the trends of techonologies used in the Software Development field. Now, after this decade of trend watching, it's interesting to reflect on the some of the other interesting aspects, non-technological, of the Software job market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can witness the impact of Covid on the job market in two big ways, both on the big cuts at the beginning of the Pandemic, as well as the move to majority remote work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see the standardization of job levels across the industry, with the now ubiquitous Senior Software Engineer role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see the rise and fall of job posting counts reveal booms and busts in the Startup and Venture Capital ecosystem. This is the one happening again right now, as January's thread, with 285 postings (top-level threads), had the lowest number of job postings in over 9 years. We have to go all the way back to 2015 and before to find levels this low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2024/january.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full December rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.hntrends.com/images/202401-ask-hn-who-is-hiring-tot.png" length="89827" type="image/png" />
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2024/january.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2024/january.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tough year for tech hiring comes to a close</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;I wasn't expecting big things from December's Ask HN: Who is hiring? thread. December is typically a slow month anyway in the hiring cycle. But, with November's thread showing a little upwards momentum, December's results would be an interesting sign if that growth could be sustained after a year of steady declines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2023/december.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full December rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.hntrends.com/images/202312-ask-hn-who-is-hiring-tot.png" length="70873" type="image/png" />
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 18:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/december.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/december.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Number of job postings climbing: up 20% in last two months</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;November's Ask HN: Who is hiring? thread showed continued growth with 375 postings, up 20% from the near all-time low in September, and up 10% over October's thread. This is a positive sign after months of declines. However, on a year-over-year basis, we're still way off of the 2022 numbers (down 30%) and the 2021 numbers dwarf where we are today (down 61% since November, 2021).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2023/november.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full November rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.hntrends.com/images/202311-ask-hn-who-is-hiring-tot.png" length="71375" type="image/png" />
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 05:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/november.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/november.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Rising: Now the most-cited technology</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;The term AI can mean many different things in the context of software development and programming. However, its significance in the current tech job market cannot be understated. The data reveals that for October's &quot;Ask HN: Who is hiring?&quot; thread, AI is the most mentioned technology term. AI was mentioned in nearly 20% of the postings. It has doubled, from 10% of postings in October, 2022, to the new peak. The only terms more popular than AI are location aspects (Remote vs onsite), experience level (Senior), and area of focus (full stack). For October, AI was more popular than any technology tracked in the history of the &quot;Ask HN: Who is hiring?&quot; thread. More popular than Python and React, the long-time dominant tech terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the number of job postings in &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37739028"&gt;October's &quot;Ask HN: Who is hiring?&quot;&lt;/a&gt; thread is up 10% over September's historic low. October's data shows that the 2023 is stabilizing a bit over the past few months from the larger drops between Spring and Summer. I continue to hear rumblings in various places software developers hang out about the current job market being very difficult, and this data does continue to back that up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2023/october.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full October rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 06:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/october.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/october.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&quot;Who is hiring?&quot; dips to another new low in September - Hacker News Hiring Trends</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37351667"&gt;September's "Ask HN: Who hiring?" thread&lt;/a&gt; hit an eight-year low, as job posts continued their downward trend. We have to go back to January 2015 to when the number of postings was this low. But, September is in thet past and a new thread goes up tomorrow (Monday) morning. With Summer now over, October's thread could be a chance for a nice Fall bump.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/september.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/september.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiring slowdown reaches new low - June 2023 Hacker News Hiring Trends</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;It should come as little surprise that the number of job postings on &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/submitted?id=whoishiring"&gt;whoishiring&lt;/a&gt; threads continues to slow heading into summer. Between the general market slowness and summer vacation season starting, June dropped to a new longtime low of 359 postings. Perhaps the lowest of what I consider the modern era of "Who is Hiring?". The last time postings were this low was January 2015. "Who is Hiring?" had only surpassed 500 postings once before then though, so its popularity as a job board was nowhere near where it is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2023/june.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full June rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 05:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/june.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/june.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote jobs drop to lowest levels post-COVID - May 2023 Hacker News Hiring Trends</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;Change is happening fast in the software developer hiring landscape. Let's jump in and take a look at the results from &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=35773707"&gt;May's Hacker News "Ask HN: Who is hiring?"&lt;/a&gt; thread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, in a positive sign, there were 431 postings (as of May 21), which marks a 12% increase over &lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2023/april.html"&gt;April&lt;/a&gt;. April's total was the lowest in over 7 years, so it's good to see some growth in job opportunites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant change for May's "Who is hiring?" thread may be the ever-evolving situation of remote work. There was a big drop in remote positions, down to just over 50%, a drop of 11% from April. Hybrid is picking up the difference for the most part still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.hntrends.com/images/202305-remote-vs-onsite-vs-hybr.svg" alt="Remote Work" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Top 10 Programming Languages&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Top 3 for May remain the same, Python, TypeScript, and Go. But, Rust gets back to #4, matching its all time high. Also getting back into the Top 10 is Swift, at #10. Swift has been been in the Top 10. I can't recall the last time it has been there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.hntrends.com/images/202305-top-10-programming-langu.svg" alt="Top 10 Programming Languages" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;AI&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the AI category, probably the most covered technology of 2023, it is hard to say with certainty if there are significant changes. Mentions of Machine Learning were down a bit, while AI was up a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.hntrends.com/images/202305-ai-vs-machine-learning-v.svg" alt="AI trends" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2023/may-remote-jobs-drop-lowest-levels-post-covid.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full May rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 02:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/may-remote-jobs-drop-lowest-levels-post-covid.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/may-remote-jobs-drop-lowest-levels-post-covid.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiring Slowdown Continues - April 2023 Hacker News Hiring Trends</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;The main theme from &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=35424807"&gt;April's Ask HN: Who is hiring?&lt;/a&gt; thread is that the downward trend on postings continues. April had 384 job postings, down almost 13% from March. This is the lowest total since December of 2015. Year over year, April 2023 is down 51% from April 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2023/april.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full April rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/april.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/april.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>March 2023 Hacker News Hiring Trends</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;The Software Developer job industry is facing many changing dynamics, and the data from the &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34983767"&gt;"Ask HN: Who is hiring?" thread on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; is a great way to track the changes. From the overall drop in job postings, the return of work to the office, to the rise in AI technogies poised to cause disruption to the way we work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there is the total number of job postings, at the lowest levels in years. For March, there are 440 (as of this writing) top level comments on the thread, which represent individual job postings. This is up a bit from last month's count of 394, but prior to Feburary, there wasn't a month with less than 480 postings since December, 2015. This analysis was also confirmed/cited earlier this week over at &lt;a href="https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/is-there-a-drop-in-software-engineer"&gt;The Pragmatic Engineer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://www.hntrends.com/images/hacker-news-hiring-trends-remote-vs-onsite-march-2023.png" alt="March 2023 Hacker News Hiring Trends: Remote vs Onsite" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2023/march.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full March rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 02:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/march.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2023/march.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>November 2022 Hacker News Hiring Trends</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;What a difference a year makes. The number of job postings in the &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33422129"&gt;&quot;Ask HN: Who is hiring?&quot; thread for November&lt;/a&gt; bounced back a bit from October's near all-time low, but was still way down from last year. For November, there were 555 postings (top level comments), up 13% over October. But, postings are down year-over-year, 45%, from November 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust programming language has moved up to to the fourth most popular language. The language has &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.blog/2022/06/22/asked-and-answered-the-results-for-the-2022-developer-survey-are-here/"&gt;enjoyed success as the "most loved" language for many years&lt;/a&gt; and it has continually picked up momentem in the Who is hiring? thread now too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;React is still the top &quot;tech&quot; term in the rankings. However, it hit a 5 year low last month, and stayed at near the same level this month at 22.88% of postings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2022/november.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full November rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2022/november.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2022/november.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>June 2022 Hacker News Hiring Trends</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;Python is once again the top programming language after losing to TypeScript the last two months. Previous to the last two months' defeat, Python had been the top programming language for six years. Will it stay on top again, or will this battle between Python and TypeScript go back and forth into the future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2022/june.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full June rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2022/june.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2022/june.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>May 2022 Hacker News Hiring Trends</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;For May, at the top of the rankings, everything stayed pretty much the same as it was in April. Remote hiring is still very popular, with 75% of postings including it. On the techonology front, React is still the only tech term in the top 5, with about 26% of postings including it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one new entrant in the Top 20.  Terraform, the popular Infrastructure as code (IaC) tool from HashiCorp, had a strong month and makes its debut in the Top 20. AI is back in the in the Top #20 after briefly dropping lower in previous months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of note for technology on the way down or out, Hadoop logged 0 mentions in May, the second time in 3 months. The platform that was on the forefront of Big Data a decade ago, has fallen out of favor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Total Postings&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May has been a tumultous month in the software hiring market. With &lt;a href="https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-scoop-12?s=r"&gt;layoffs and hiring freezes at several companies&lt;/a&gt;, the near-term future faces uncertainty. May's &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=31235968"&gt;Ask HN: Who is Hiring?&lt;/a&gt; did see a slight bump with total postings up 4% over April. But, with the bulk of the postings coming earlier in the month of May, that growth may well have dried up in the weeks since. With the June thread kicking off in a couple days, we'll see soon enough how the overall hiring marketing is impacting this specific niche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2022/may.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full May rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 01:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2022/may.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2022/may.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>April 2022 Hacker News Hiring Trends</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;TypeScript has dethroned Python. For the first time in over six years, there is a new #1 programming language in the rankings with TypeScript jumping ahead of Python. Python has had a remarkable run, taking the top spot among programming languages since March, 2016. TypeScript steps up to the top spot in the same year it turns ten years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last two years alone, TypeScript has jumped from around ~12% of postings to nearly ~20% in April's postings. I am curious about what is driving this recent surge. Is it solely because JavaScript development is steadily migrating to TypeScript, or is it because new waves of developers and use cases are calling for it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2022/april.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full April rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2022/april.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2022/april.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>March 2022 Hacker News Hiring Trends</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;Checking in with a quick March Update since it's been a few months. The list of terms used to analyze the job postings has been refreshed with some newer and popular technolgies, technologies that have been gaining ground over the last year. A few of the newer technologies that have cracked the "Rising" list with entries include: FastAPI, Tailwind CSS, web3, Clickhouse, and Flutter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back up at the top of the charts, the remote hiring trend appears to have peaked, dropping back from an all time high of ~77% of postings to this month with ~74% of postings. Not a big drop, and that's already amazingly high, but the trend is not climbing higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking further at the top 20, it has remained very stable over the last year. Techology-wise, React, Python, and TypeScript are still dominating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type the technologies or software-related terms of interest to you into the comparison tool above to see how they are faring. What trends do you see?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2022/march.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends and view the full March rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 03:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2022/march.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2022/march.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Work trend still climbing - Hacker News Hiring Trends (December 2021)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;In the final month of 2021, the remote work trend that exploded in mid-2020 due to the COVID pandemic shows no sign of slowing. Remote-friendly positions account for nearly 77% of the job postings in December's "Ask HN: Who is hiring?" thread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for technology trends, there are a couple of interesting updates. First, Java dropped to the #8 programming language, tied with C++. This is likely the lowest, relatvie to other programming languages, Java has ever been in the ten years worth of data tracked here. Ten years ago, Java was peaking at 20% of postings. Now, it's down to about 6%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;React is still on top of the tech world, though its trend looks to be plateauing. Might we see it on a downward trend in 2022?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, 2021 was the year that Web3 made a big spash onto the scene and so Web3 has now been added to the trends here to track its impact on tech jobs. I'm sure it's only a matter of time until we see job postings asking for 10 years of Web3 experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2021/dec-remote-work-trend-still-climbing.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full December rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 02:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2021/dec-remote-work-trend-still-climbing.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2021/dec-remote-work-trend-still-climbing.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>July 2021 Hacker News Hiring Trends</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;For July, jobs postings in the "Ask HN: Who is hiring?" thread remained strong with 65% year-over-year growth compared to July of 2020. At the time of this post, there were 931 top level comments in the July thread which represent job postings being analyzed. This is a bit of a dip from June's all time record high number of 1040 posts, but that's not too unusual looking at past years' summer time hiring dips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Beyond technology trends&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the COVID Pandemic sigificantly altering the work landscape between Office and Remote, I have added several non-tech terms into the analyis. The result of this is that the "Remote" keyword is the top term by far, with over 70% of positiona being offered as remote. If companies delay return to office plans due to the resurgence of COVID then this trend will likely remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking further at the non-tech results, thre are a couple of interesting trends to watch. First, the type of developer positions being advertised include variations on the preferred candidate focus between &lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2021/july.html?compare=Back+End&amp;compare=Front+End&amp;compare=Full+Stack"&gt;Back-end vs Front-end vs Full-stack&lt;/a&gt; with Back-end winning for now. Meanwhile, when it comes to experience, &lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2021/july.html?compare=Senior&amp;compare=Junior"&gt;Senior level developers are being sought 10 times more frequently than Junior developers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where is the hot Tech?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has not been a breakout tech trend that I can spot yet this year. React, Python, AWS, and TypeScript are still at the top when it comes to technology related terms. The Go programming language is perhaps the biggest trend as &lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2021/july.html?compare=golang&amp;compare=ruby&amp;compare=java"&gt;Go has begun to separate from Ruby and Java a bit&lt;/a&gt;. Kubernetes has made a push into the top 20 as well over the past year, but both the rise of Go and Kubernetes have been happening for a few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2021/july.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full July rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2021/july.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2021/july.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New record for job postings - Hacker News Hiring Trends (June 2021)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;Hiring is on fire for software developers as June set an all time record for the number of postings to the "Who is hiring?" thread with 1040 top level comments. This was only the third time, ever, surpassing 1000 comments and breaks the previous record set in May, 2018. This also nearly doubles the count from one year ago in June, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2021/jun-new-record-hacker-news-jobs-postings.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full June rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 21:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2021/jun-new-record-hacker-news-jobs-postings.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2021/jun-new-record-hacker-news-jobs-postings.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Work is now the norm - Hacker News Hiring Trends (February 2021)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;The new year and a new way of working in the Covid era allows us to take a fresh look at hiring trends on &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25989764"&gt;Hacker News' whoishiring threads&lt;/a&gt;. This month, we are going beyond just technology. A few new terms have been added to the analysis, looking at software job specialization (frontend, backend, full-stack), and job experience/level (Principal, Staff, Senior, Junior).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, first, and not all that surprisingly, the biggest change this month is from checking in on remote work. Remote postings now account for about 2/3 of all postings, up from about 30% a year ago, pre-Covid. Remote is now the most common attribute of job postings, drowing out perennial winner React.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second finding from the month is that hiring is ramping up. The spring is usually when the total number of posts starts spiking for the year, but this month had the third most posts ever in the history of the whoishiring thread. This is a significant rebound from &lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2020/may-big-drop-developer-job-postings.html"&gt;last May when it was noted that jobs were dropping&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2021/feb-remote-work-now-norm.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full February rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 01:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2021/feb-remote-work-now-norm.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2021/feb-remote-work-now-norm.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020 was a year unlike any other, but tech tools didn't change much - HN Hiring Trends (December 2020)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;I think it's safe to say that the World experienced unprecedented change this year with the Covid-19 Pandemic and the response to it. But, even with a shift to remote work, and a strong software job market, the tools and technologies that Software Developers used in 2020 remained very similar to the tools used in prior years. Looking at the job postings from &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25266288"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;, this data reveals very little change from what was found in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting at the top of the rankings, the Top Three this month are the exact same Top 3 from December 2019 with React, Python and AWS taking their usual positions. TypeScript did take a jump into the top 5, but as an extension of the JavaScript ecosystem, it's essentially taken JavaScript's spot. Otherwise 9 of last December's Top 10 are in the Top 10 this December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those that live on the bleeding edge, it may have even been a disappointing year since there was no obvious breakout tech in 2020. Where 2019 had TypeScript and 2018 had Kubernetes, there was nothing that experienced a similar meteoric rise in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead to 2021, what technologies should we keeping an eye on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2020/dec-year-unlike-any-other-tech-tools-didnt-change-much.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full December rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2020/dec-year-unlike-any-other-tech-tools-didnt-change-much.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2020/dec-year-unlike-any-other-tech-tools-didnt-change-much.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big drop in developer job postings - HN Hiring Trends (May 2020)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;With the midway point of 2020 fast approaching, and the world in the midst of perhaps the largest shift in employment in my lifetime, it seems like an appropriate time time to take a peek at how software job trends are looking through the lens of &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23042618"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ask HN: Who is hiring?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a regular, monthly collection of software development job postings. The summary posts on hntrends.com usually focus on specific technologies that are gaining or losing adoption, but first let's look at how Covid-19 is affecting this specific job board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my two perspectives, this data and my own job it should be no surprise that Software Development jobs have been significantly impacted by Covid-19. As companies halt hiring and announce furloughs and layoffs, the trend is showing clearly on &lt;em&gt;Ask HN: Who is hiring?&lt;/em&gt;. April and May both dropped sharply, 39% decreases over the same month in 2019. May is traditionally the peak month of the year for postings on HN, let's hope the summer and fall can rebound to beat May this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, onto the tech changes, or lack thereof. React still reigns supreme in the number 1 spot with Python and AWS holding steady in second and third place, respectively. This is the same top three as April as well as the same top three as last May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking further through the rankings, it looks like TypeScript is the one making the biggest push in 2020, just like it was in 2019. TypeScript has held the #5 spot nearly all of 2020. In fact 4 of the top 10 are JavaScript related as JavaScript continues its dominance of the web stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2020/may-big-drop-developer-job-postings.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full May rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2020/may-big-drop-developer-job-postings.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2020/may-big-drop-developer-job-postings.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another year on top for React - Hacker News Hiring Trends (December 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;Just as it did last year, React completed the full calendar 2019 as the
top tech in &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21683554"&gt;Ask HN: Who is hiring?&lt;/a&gt;
extending its win streak to 31 months. React has been trending down in
recent months and December marks its lowest share of the year, at just
over 25% of postings. But, the runner up, Python, still has a long way
to go to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some notable big movers in December. Machine Learning made
a jump from #12 to #4. While Go jumped back into the Top 10 overall
and was the second most popular programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other big story for 2019 would have to be TypeScript which is now a
Top 10 contender every month and at parity with JavaScript regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/dec-another-year-on-top-for-react.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full December rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 22:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/dec-another-year-on-top-for-react.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/dec-another-year-on-top-for-react.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GraphQL Reaches Top 20 - Hacker News Hiring Trends (November 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;GraphQL continues a fast rise that mirrors what popular JavaScript frameworks have done. November marks GraphQL's first time in the top 20 of techologies mentioned on the &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21419536"&gt;Hacker News "Who is Hiring?" thread.&lt;/a&gt; GraphQL was &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10153497"&gt;first mentioned in September, 2015&lt;/a&gt; and joins TypeScript as one of the newest entries in the Top 20 over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the top of rankings, React won again, extending its win streak to 30th month in a row. A full 2 and a half years and running as the top tech. The Top 3 remain unchanged with Python #2 and AWS #3. JavaScript rose 2 spots to #4 and PostgreSQL kept its spot at #5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/nov-graphql-reaches-top-20.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full November rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/nov-graphql-reaches-top-20.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/nov-graphql-reaches-top-20.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No sign of React Falling Back - Hacker News Hiring Trends (October 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;Fall hiring season was in full swing in &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21126014"&gt;October's "Ask HN: Who is hiring?" thread&lt;/a&gt; with the usual technologies in demand. React ran away with the top spot again, showing no sign of weakness as it beat Python by 8 percentage points and won for the 29th month in a row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, there was not a lot of movement in the top rankings. The top 3 remain unchnaged from last month. TypeScript did slide back a few  spots, while Full Stack and JavaScript reclaimed some ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/oct-no-sign-of-react-falling-back.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full October rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 02:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/oct-no-sign-of-react-falling-back.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/oct-no-sign-of-react-falling-back.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React reaches 30% of all posts (September 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;React continues on the path towards software ubiquity as it cracks the 30% barrier. That means 30% of the job postings on &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20867123"&gt;September's "Ask HN: Who is hiring?" thread&lt;/a&gt; mentioned React. Not since Septepmber, 2014 when JavaScript cracked 30% has there been a technology mentioned so frequently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of software uqiquity, JavaScript is the foundational technology for both React and TypeScript but JavaScript itself has declined from that peak of 30% five years ago, to 12% in the latest results. JavaScript was also passed by TypeScript for the #2 programming language. As more technologies are built on top of JavaScript, the need to have JavaScript skills either becomes so essential as to not needing to be stated, or not necessary because of the new abstractions. Is this JavaScript realizing the &lt;a href="https://www.hanselman.com/blog/JavaScriptIsAssemblyLanguageForTheWebSematicMarkupIsDeadCleanVsMachinecodedHTML.aspx"&gt;prediction to becoming the assembly language for the web?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/sep-react-reaches-thirty-percent-posts.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full September rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/sep-react-reaches-thirty-percent-posts.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/sep-react-reaches-thirty-percent-posts.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript reaches the Top 10 (August 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;While React won again, its 27th month in a row, TypeScript looks like August's top story, as it cracks the Top 10 for the first time. TypeScript reached the Top 20 last September and continued to climb over the past twelve months. TypeScript appears to have gotten swept up in Reacts ecosystem as developers use TypeScript to create React apps. TypeScript is even the 3rd most popular programming language overall now, jumping over the Go Programming Languge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kuberetes is another climber, reaching #12, and matching its all time best performance. It's now neck and neck with Docker as those two continue to feed off each other to grow the containerized application industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/aug-typescript-reaches-top-10.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full August rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 8 Sep 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/aug-typescript-reaches-top-10.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/aug-typescript-reaches-top-10.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't worry, React is still dominating - Hacker News Hiring Trends (July 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;Welcome back! Hacker News Hiring Trends returns from a Spring Break to get caught up on 2019 technology trends. It may come as a surprise, but React is still on top, running its win streak past 2 years. React first won in June 2017 and has been on top ever since. No other technology has enjoyed such a string of success in the 8 year history of "Who is hiring".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it has been a few months since I last posted, it does allow other areas of software development to experience a shake-up and surprisingly programming languages are seeing some interesting trends. Normally, programming languages have been fairly static relative to the faster moving area of frameworks, but a number of programming languages are appearing frequently in job postings. The Go programming language is establishing itself as the third most popular programming language and consistently placing in the Top 10 overall. Rust is another programming language making news as it records its first appearance in the Top 10 programming languages, knocking out C in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/jul-dont-worry-react-still-dominating.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full July rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 05:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/jul-dont-worry-react-still-dominating.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/jul-dont-worry-react-still-dominating.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL vs MySQL no longer close - Hacker News Hiring Trends (March 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;With React's incredible rise and dominance, this month marks 22 wins in a row, it becomes an interesting challenge to find other trends in the rankings. One such trend worth mentioning is the database battles. A few years ago, the competition between PostgreSQL and MySQL was close with each going back and forth. Sometime around 2015, PostgreSQL began to consistently beat MySQL and fast forward to 2019, it's no longer close with PostgreSQL opening a 10% lead over MySQL this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Top 5 went React, Python, AWS, PostgreSQL and JavaScript this month. JavaScript climbing to #5 is the only change there, ironically trading places with Node.js. The rest of the Top 10 was mostly the same with minor bumps for most of 6-10. Docker's still knocking on the door at 11 while Kubernetes has gained the most momentum towards a Top 10 finish in the last year, though actually reaching the Top 10 may take some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/mar-postgresql-vs-mysql-no-longer-close.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full March rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/mar-postgresql-vs-mysql-no-longer-close.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/mar-postgresql-vs-mysql-no-longer-close.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React win streak reaches 20 months - Hacker News Hiring Trends (January 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;Will React ever be defeated? That is the question I am beginning to ask each month as React continues to dominate the whoishiring posts on Hacker News. You have to think React can't continue this dominance indefinitely, it will begin a decline at some point. But, when, and what will dethrone it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the rankings look similar to previous months, including a Top 5 that is exactly the same as last month. 5-10 saw a little bit of movement with Postgresql moving up 4 spots from 10 to 6. Go cracked the top 10 again with a jump from 11 to 8, becoming the third most popular programming language in the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/jan-react-win-streak-reaches-20-months.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full January rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 06:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/jan-react-win-streak-reaches-20-months.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/jan-react-win-streak-reaches-20-months.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React closes out dominant 2018 - Hacker News Hiring Trends (December 2018)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;The story of 2018, much like 2017, remains to be React as it becomes the first technology to remain on top for an entire calendar year. React also runs its win streak to an incredible nineteen months in a row. Looking at the larger world of JavaScript libraries does not reveal any emerging threats to React on the horizon. Angular is trending down, Vue.js is still in search of a jump to the next level and Ember remains flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as programming languages go, Python is mirroring React's overall dominance, claiming the crown as most popular programming language for the past nineteen months. It was last topped by JavaScript in May, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 23:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/dec-react-closes-out-dominant-2018.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/dec-react-closes-out-dominant-2018.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React still on top; Containers are hot</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;November's job postings were in line with most of 2018 as React remains on top with a strong lead again after a close call last month. If this holds for React in December, it'll have been in the top spot for the full calendar year. That will be the first time a technology will have that distinction in these rankings. If that's not enough React, it's also worth mentioning that November, 2018 marks the 2 year anniversary of &lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2016/november.html"&gt;React's first win&lt;/a&gt; in November, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 06:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/nov-react-still-top-containers-hot.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/nov-react-still-top-containers-hot.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React holds off Python (October 2018)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;React is still on top after a whopping seventeen months, but it did have its closest finish in almost a year, beating second place Python by just over a percentage point. JavaScript made a strong jump to third place with AWS and Node.js rounding out the Top 5 for October.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 05:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/oct-react-holds-off-python.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/oct-react-holds-off-python.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript makes its move (September 2018)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;While there was a little bit of a shake-up internally within the Top 5 in September compared to previous months, the players mostly look familiar. At the top, React claimed its sixteenth win in a row, a streak that began in June, 2017. Following up in second as usual, Python continued its own streak. Making a first appearance in the Top 5 was "Full Stack", proving that the term is still alive and well. Rounding out the top 5 was node.js, its first Top 5 finish since May.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/sep-typescript-makes-move.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/sep-typescript-makes-move.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer hiring heats up; React still on fire</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;The Top 5 remained exactly the same in August as it was in July with React on top followed by Python, AWS, Postgresql and JavaScript. This is React's fifteenth month in a row in the top spot. Though React has slid back in terms of share over the last quarter after peaking in June, it's still in a dominant position.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/aug-summer-hiring-heats-up-react-fire.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/aug-summer-hiring-heats-up-react-fire.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Programming Languages</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;For most months, this post examines technologies across the sprectrum of software development, from languages to frameworks to products. And, that data is all still here for you to examine as well. But, I thought it would be interesting to take a look at the state of Programming Languages specifically as their trends can often be obscured in the overall analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 22:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/jul-top-ten-programming-languages.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/jul-top-ten-programming-languages.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No signs of slowing for React</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;React reached new heights in June with a mention in over 28% of postings, easily taking the top spot for the thirteenth month in a row. The highest ever for a technology was 32% for JavaScript nearly four years ago. Can React challenge it? With React's adoption on the web and for mobile app developments with React Native, it presents an attractive platform for many developers to explore. But, front-end technologies have a history of being replaced for the hot new thing, so how long can React stay on top?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent notable movers, Node.js (into the top 5 last month) and Go (first top 10 appearance 2 months ago), could not continue their climbs, and have leveled off a bit, though still near their peaks.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 6 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/jun-no-signs-of-slowing-for-react.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/jun-no-signs-of-slowing-for-react.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Node.js breaks into the Top 5</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;In another sign of JavaScript's ubiquity, Node.js became the second JavaScript related technology to surpass mentions of JavaScript itself. Node.js took the #4 spot in May, its first time in the top 5, and just ahead of JavaScript. React was the first to do so, and React also continued its streak of wins, taking the top spot for the 12th month in a row, sustaining its rank for a complete year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May also marked an all time high in total postings, with more than 1000 postings for only the 2nd time ever and was up 17% over last May.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/may-node-js-breaks-into-top-5.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/may-node-js-breaks-into-top-5.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Golang jumps into Top 10</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;The Go Programming Language (golang) made its first appearance in the Top 10 and is now the third most popular programming language in the rankings. Go jumped over both Java and Ruby this month. First released in 2012, Go has climbed steadily as its popularity grows, and was mentioned in over 10% of postings in April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was looking forward to a month without writing about React, but that will have to wait. React easily won the rankings again, its 11th win in a row. But, not only that, it's still climbing, reaching its all time best of over 26% of postings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are couple of changes to the tracking worth mentioning this month. First, Amazon's DynamoDB has replaced Riak as the top key-value store and has been added to the NoSQL category below. Second, GraphQL, Facebook's popular query language for APIs has been added thanks to Jrgen Orehj Erichsen keen eye. GraphQL is one to keep an eye on its already cracked the top 50 in less than 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/apr-golang-jumps-into-top-10.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/apr-golang-jumps-into-top-10.html
      </guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
