<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News Hiring Trends</title>
    <description>Stay up to date with the most popular programming languanges, databases, web application and software development technologies on Hacker News whoishiring posts</description>
    <link>https://www.hntrends.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.hntrends.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>GraphQL Reaches Top 20 - Hacker News Hiring Trends (November 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;GraphQL continues a fast rise that mirrors what popular JavaScript frameworks have done. November marks GraphQL's first time in the top 20 of techologies mentioned on the &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21419536"&gt;Hacker News "Who is Hiring?" thread.&lt;/a&gt; GraphQL was &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10153497"&gt;first mentioned in September, 2015&lt;/a&gt; and joins TypeScript as one of the newest entries in the Top 20 over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the top of rankings, React won again, extending its win streak to 30th month in a row. A full 2 and a half years and running as the top tech. The Top 3 remain unchanged with Python #2 and AWS #3. JavaScript rose 2 spots to #4 and PostgreSQL kept its spot at #5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/nov-graphql-reaches-top-20.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full September rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/nov-graphql-reaches-top-20.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/nov-graphql-reaches-top-20.html
      </guid>
    </item>    
    <item>
      <title>No sign of React Falling Back - Hacker News Hiring Trends (October 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;Fall hiring season was in full swing in &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21126014"&gt;October's "Ask HN: Who is hiring?" thread&lt;/a&gt; with the usual technologies in demand. React ran away with the top spot again, showing no sign of weakness as it beat Python by 8 percentage points and won for the 29th month in a row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, there was not a lot of movement in the top rankings. The top 3 remain unchnaged from last month. TypeScript did slide back a few  spots, while Full Stack and JavaScript reclaimed some ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/oct-no-sign-of-react-falling-back.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full September rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 02:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/oct-no-sign-of-react-falling-back.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/oct-no-sign-of-react-falling-back.html
      </guid>
    </item>    
    <item>
      <title>React reaches 30% of all posts (September 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;React continues on the path towards software ubiquity as it cracks the 30% barrier. That means 30% of the job postings on &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20867123"&gt;September's "Ask HN: Who is hiring?" thread&lt;/a&gt; mentioned React. Not since Septepmber, 2014 when JavaScript cracked 30% has there been a technology mentioned so frequently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of software uqiquity, JavaScript is the foundational technology for both React and TypeScript but JavaScript itself has declined from that peak of 30% five years ago, to 12% in the latest results. JavaScript was also passed by TypeScript for the #2 programming language. As more technologies are built on top of JavaScript, the need to have JavaScript skills either becomes so essential as to not needing to be stated, or not necessary because of the new abstractions. Is this JavaScript realizing the &lt;a href="https://www.hanselman.com/blog/JavaScriptIsAssemblyLanguageForTheWebSematicMarkupIsDeadCleanVsMachinecodedHTML.aspx"&gt;prediction to becoming the assembly language for the web?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/sep-react-reaches-thirty-percent-posts.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full September rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/sep-react-reaches-thirty-percent-posts.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/sep-react-reaches-thirty-percent-posts.html
      </guid>
    </item>    
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript reaches the Top 10 (August 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;While React won again, its 27th month in a row, TypeScript looks like August's top story, as it cracks the Top 10 for the first time. TypeScript reached the Top 20 last September and continued to climb over the past twelve months. TypeScript appears to have gotten swept up in Reacts ecosystem as developers use TypeScript to create React apps. TypeScript is even the 3rd most popular programming language overall now, jumping over the Go Programming Languge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kuberetes is another climber, reaching #12, and matching its all time best performance. It's now neck and neck with Docker as those two continue to feed off each other to grow the containerized application industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/aug-typescript-reaches-top-10.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full August rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 8 Sep 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/aug-typescript-reaches-top-10.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/aug-typescript-reaches-top-10.html
      </guid>
    </item>    
    <item>
      <title>Don't worry, React is still dominating - Hacker News Hiring Trends (July 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;Welcome back! Hacker News Hiring Trends returns from a Spring Break to get caught up on 2019 technology trends. It may come as a surprise, but React is still on top, running its win streak past 2 years. React first won in June 2017 and has been on top ever since. No other technology has enjoyed such a string of success in the 8 year history of "Who is hiring".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it has been a few months since I last posted, it does allow other areas of software development to experience a shake-up and surprisingly programming languages are seeing some interesting trends. Normally, programming languages have been fairly static relative to the faster moving area of frameworks, but a number of programming languages are appearing frequently in job postings. The Go programming language is establishing itself as the third most popular programming language and consistently placing in the Top 10 overall. Rust is another programming language making news as it records its first appearance in the Top 10 programming languages, knocking out C in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/jul-dont-worry-react-still-dominating.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full July rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 05:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/jul-dont-worry-react-still-dominating.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/jul-dont-worry-react-still-dominating.html
      </guid>
    </item>    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL vs MySQL no longer close - Hacker News Hiring Trends (March 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;With React's incredible rise and dominance, this month marks 22 wins in a row, it becomes an interesting challenge to find other trends in the rankings. One such trend worth mentioning is the database battles. A few years ago, the competition between PostgreSQL and MySQL was close with each going back and forth. Sometime around 2015, PostgreSQL began to consistently beat MySQL and fast forward to 2019, it's no longer close with PostgreSQL opening a 10% lead over MySQL this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Top 5 went React, Python, AWS, PostgreSQL and JavaScript this month. JavaScript climbing to #5 is the only change there, ironically trading places with Node.js. The rest of the Top 10 was mostly the same with minor bumps for most of 6-10. Docker's still knocking on the door at 11 while Kubernetes has gained the most momentum towards a Top 10 finish in the last year, though actually reaching the Top 10 may take some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/mar-postgresql-vs-mysql-no-longer-close.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full March rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/mar-postgresql-vs-mysql-no-longer-close.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/mar-postgresql-vs-mysql-no-longer-close.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React win streak reaches 20 months - Hacker News Hiring Trends (January 2019)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;Will React ever be defeated? That is the question I am beginning to ask each month as React continues to dominate the whoishiring posts on Hacker News. You have to think React can't continue this dominance indefinitely, it will begin a decline at some point. But, when, and what will dethrone it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the rankings look similar to previous months, including a Top 5 that is exactly the same as last month. 5-10 saw a little bit of movement with Postgresql moving up 4 spots from 10 to 6. Go cracked the top 10 again with a jump from 11 to 8, becoming the third most popular programming language in the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2019/jan-react-win-streak-reaches-20-months.html"&gt;Visit the site&lt;/a&gt; to compare trends by technology and view the full January rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 06:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/jan-react-win-streak-reaches-20-months.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2019/jan-react-win-streak-reaches-20-months.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React closes out dominant 2018 - Hacker News Hiring Trends (December 2018)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;The story of 2018, much like 2017, remains to be React as it becomes the first technology to remain on top for an entire calendar year. React also runs its win streak to an incredible nineteen months in a row. Looking at the larger world of JavaScript libraries does not reveal any emerging threats to React on the horizon. Angular is trending down, Vue.js is still in search of a jump to the next level and Ember remains flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as programming languages go, Python is mirroring React's overall dominance, claiming the crown as most popular programming language for the past nineteen months. It was last topped by JavaScript in May, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 23:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/dec-react-closes-out-dominant-2018.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/dec-react-closes-out-dominant-2018.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React still on top; Containers are hot</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;November's job postings were in line with most of 2018 as React remains on top with a strong lead again after a close call last month. If this holds for React in December, it'll have been in the top spot for the full calendar year. That will be the first time a technology will have that distinction in these rankings. If that's not enough React, it's also worth mentioning that November, 2018 marks the 2 year anniversary of &lt;a href="https://www.hntrends.com/2016/november.html"&gt;React's first win&lt;/a&gt; in November, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 06:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/nov-react-still-top-containers-hot.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/nov-react-still-top-containers-hot.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React holds off Python (October 2018)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;React is still on top after a whopping seventeen months, but it did have its closest finish in almost a year, beating second place Python by just over a percentage point. JavaScript made a strong jump to third place with AWS and Node.js rounding out the Top 5 for October.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 05:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/oct-react-holds-off-python.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/oct-react-holds-off-python.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript makes its move (September 2018)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;While there was a little bit of a shake-up internally within the Top 5 in September compared to previous months, the players mostly look familiar. At the top, React claimed its sixteenth win in a row, a streak that began in June, 2017. Following up in second as usual, Python continued its own streak. Making a first appearance in the Top 5 was "Full Stack", proving that the term is still alive and well. Rounding out the top 5 was node.js, its first Top 5 finish since May.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/sep-typescript-makes-move.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/sep-typescript-makes-move.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer hiring heats up; React still on fire</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;The Top 5 remained exactly the same in August as it was in July with React on top followed by Python, AWS, Postgresql and JavaScript. This is React's fifteenth month in a row in the top spot. Though React has slid back in terms of share over the last quarter after peaking in June, it's still in a dominant position.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/aug-summer-hiring-heats-up-react-fire.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/aug-summer-hiring-heats-up-react-fire.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Programming Languages</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;For most months, this post examines technologies across the sprectrum of software development, from languages to frameworks to products. And, that data is all still here for you to examine as well. But, I thought it would be interesting to take a look at the state of Programming Languages specifically as their trends can often be obscured in the overall analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 22:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/jul-top-ten-programming-languages.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/jul-top-ten-programming-languages.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No signs of slowing for React</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;React reached new heights in June with a mention in over 28% of postings, easily taking the top spot for the thirteenth month in a row. The highest ever for a technology was 32% for JavaScript nearly four years ago. Can React challenge it? With React's adoption on the web and for mobile app developments with React Native, it presents an attractive platform for many developers to explore. But, front-end technologies have a history of being replaced for the hot new thing, so how long can React stay on top?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent notable movers, Node.js (into the top 5 last month) and Go (first top 10 appearance 2 months ago), could not continue their climbs, and have leveled off a bit, though still near their peaks.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 6 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/jun-no-signs-of-slowing-for-react.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/jun-no-signs-of-slowing-for-react.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Node.js breaks into the Top 5</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;In another sign of JavaScript's ubiquity, Node.js became the second JavaScript related technology to surpass mentions of JavaScript itself. Node.js took the #4 spot in May, its first time in the top 5, and just ahead of JavaScript. React was the first to do so, and React also continued its streak of wins, taking the top spot for the 12th month in a row, sustaining its rank for a complete year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May also marked an all time high in total postings, with more than 1000 postings for only the 2nd time ever and was up 17% over last May.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/may-node-js-breaks-into-top-5.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/may-node-js-breaks-into-top-5.html
      </guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Golang jumps into Top 10</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;The Go Programming Language (golang) made its first appearance in the Top 10 and is now the third most popular programming language in the rankings. Go jumped over both Java and Ruby this month. First released in 2012, Go has climbed steadily as its popularity grows, and was mentioned in over 10% of postings in April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was looking forward to a month without writing about React, but that will have to wait. React easily won the rankings again, its 11th win in a row. But, not only that, it's still climbing, reaching its all time best of over 26% of postings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are couple of changes to the tracking worth mentioning this month. First, Amazon's DynamoDB has replaced Riak as the top key-value store and has been added to the NoSQL category below. Second, GraphQL, Facebook's popular query language for APIs has been added thanks to Jørgen Orehøj Erichsen keen eye. GraphQL is one to keep an eye on its already cracked the top 50 in less than 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/apr-golang-jumps-into-top-10.html
      </link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://www.hntrends.com/2018/apr-golang-jumps-into-top-10.html
      </guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>